迈克: 我有一些事情要说.
Mike: I got something I'd like to say.
奶奶:迈克,你说吧.
Grandma: Go ahead Mike.
迈克:首先我想谢谢妈妈和爸爸,
Mike: First I'd like to thank Mom and Dad and...
以及艾码奶奶和瓦力爷爷,
and Grandma Erma and Grandpa Wally,
是他们让我们明白了爱情和婚姻是多么的伟大.同时,
for showing us all how great love and marriage really can be.
我也为大家带来了一个惊喜.
And, I've also got kind of a surprise for everybody.
杰森:吼吼吼,有好戏看啦.
Jason: Ho ho ho, wait till you hear this.
麦琪:你知道是什么事情吗?
Maggie: You know what's coming?
杰森:当然,没什么事能瞒得过我.
Jason: Yeah. Nothing gets by me.
迈克:我想让大家知道...让全世界都知道...
Mike: I want you all to know... Heck, I want the whole world to know...
我爱上了朱利·卡斯提洛,我要和她结婚.
that I love Julie Costello, and I want her to be my wife.
麦琪:你早就知道这件事情了?
Maggie: You knew about this?
杰森:恩....
Jason: Err...
迈克:行了吗?
Mike: Well?
朱利:行了.
Julie: Yes.
本:什么?在捕鲸船上举行婚礼?
Ben: What! A whaler?
卡罗:难道不是一件浪漫的事情吗?到时我也要在船上举行婚礼.
Carol: Wasn't that romantic? When I get married, I want it to be on a boat.
杰森:喂,我们能不能暂时消停一下...
Jason: Hey, can we please not have any fighting for maybe...
麦琪:杰森,你都知道些什么?你是什么时候知道的呀?啊?
Maggie: What did you know Jason? And when did you know it? Huh! Huh!
杰森:麦琪,我也是一个小时前才发现他们俩在一起的,
Jason: Maggie, I only found out Mike and Julie where an item an hour ago.
而且我根本就不知道他们要举行婚礼了!
The wedding just came as a complete surprise to me!
如果我不是想让你平静下来,我早就被吓的晕倒了.
And I'd be freaked out right now too, if I weren't trying to calm you down!
麦琪:你是想让我平静下来?
Maggie: You're trying to calm me down?
杰森:是的.
Jason: Yes.
麦琪:你这是吃力不讨好.
Maggie: Well you're doing a lousy job.
你的意思是你对他们俩的婚礼的事情一点也不知道?
So you mean to tell me that you really didn't know this was coming?
杰森:我真的不知道!你没看见我目瞪口呆了吗?
Jason: I didn't! Didn't you see my eyes go "booing!"?
麦琪:好,
Maggie: Well, if that little...
我相信你,但是如果那个小...
and I'll just say it, blonde,
我就叫她女人吧,
thinks she can start out taking care of Chrissy,
以为有机会照顾克里斯,
and end up taking away my son, she has got another thing coming!!
就可以把他从我身边抢走吗?她那是做梦!
I mean after what she did,
她不会还希望我能用笑脸来欢迎她成为我们家的一员吧?
I'm expected to just smile and welcome her to our family?!
迈克:麦琪,你还没有祝福我们呢?
Mike: You didn't even congratulate us yet.
麦琪:热烈欢迎成为我们的一员!
Maggie: Welcome to our family!
本:妈妈,我们明年再进行一次家庭航海旅游,好吗?
Ben: Mom, can we go on a family cruise again next year?
麦琪:本,没有问题,等在我们家开凿出一条河道就可以了.
Maggie: Sure Ben, right after we have a family route canal.
本:哦,对了,我想起来了,
Ben: Oh by the way Mom, that reminds me; before we left to take Julie home,
在我们送朱利回家前,迈克说他和朱利结婚后,我就可以住在他的房间了.
Mike said, I get his apartment after he gets married.
麦琪:哦,这是迈克说的?
Maggie: Oh, is that what Mike says?
看来,他为所有人都做好了决定;真好.
So, he's making decisions for everybody now; how nice.
你说如果我把克里斯抱到楼上,迈克会有意见吗?
Do you think it would be OK with Mike, if I took Chrissy upstairs?
本:当然不会.我认为他应该不会...啊,我刚才说什么来着?
Ben: Sure. I don't think he'd... What did I say?
卡罗:本,本,本,本,你真是个四肢发达,头脑简单的家伙.你难道没有发现从迈克公布要结婚的消息开始,爸爸和妈妈有多紧张吗?
Carol: Ben, Ben, Ben, Ben, so big in body, so small in brain. Haven't you noticed, since Mike's big announcement, how tense Mom and Dad have been?
本:爸爸和妈妈一直都是这样的.你在哪个房间长大的?
Ben: Mom and Dad are always tense. What house did you grow up in?
卡罗:本,你清醒点,
Carol: Ben, wake up and smell the nuptials!
仔细想想迈克的婚礼!我的意思是说爸妈不希望迈克结婚.
I mean the last thing they want is for Mike to get married.
本:那他怎么得到欲望满足?
Ben: How's he ever gonna have sex?
卡罗:别老想着性.问题是,爸妈无知而又固执的认为,迈克连自己的臭袜子都不愿意捡起来,根本就不适合结婚,因为他太年轻,没有责任心.
Carol: Forget about sex. The problem is, Mom and Dad in their foolish blindness, think that if Mike can't pick up his own dirty socks, he's too young and irresponsible for marriage.
杰森:哦,卡罗,
Jason: Oh, is that what it is Carol?
真是你说的那样吗?
Well, thank you for you razor-sharp analysis.
还是要谢谢你中肯的分析.我想你的智慧应该是来源于你所抚养的孩子们吧.
I'm sure your wisdom comes from all the kids you've raised!
卡罗:事实上...我走了.
Carol: Well, actually...bye.
本:爸爸,我认为我们没有谈论到性.
Ben: Dad, all I know is, we weren't talking about sex.
麦琪:杰森,我们开始就不应该请朱利来这里上班.
Maggie: Jason, we should have never hired Julie in the first place.
我的意思是说,我们不应该让她和迈克走的那么近,
I mean, putting her and Mike, two attractive young people in close contact;
这样很容易产生感情,其实我们是自食其果.
we were just begging for something like this to happen.
杰森:麦琪,毕竟是我请她来的.你不需要责怪你自己了.
Jason: Hey, Maggie, after all I hired her. You shouldn't blame yourself.
麦琪:我没有.
Maggie: I wasn't.
迈克:那你就说"要"好了.
Mike: Then, you say "yes".
朱利:但是,我还没有要小孩的准备呀.
Julie: But, I'm not ready to have kids.
迈克:那你就说"不要"好了.
Mike: Then, just say "no".
朱利:可是,如果他们问...
Julie: But, what if they ask...
迈克:朱利, 朱利,看着我,听我说.我们讨论的是我的家人,不是什么期末考试,不用答题,也不用他们来评分.
Mike: Listen, Julie, Julie, look. This is not some kind of final exam, where they hand out tests and grade our papers. This is my family we are talking about.
朱利:你说的对.
Julie: You're right.
迈克:你看,我们只是坐在一起吃些面包...
Mike: Yeah, look, we're just gonna sit down and we're gonna break bread
可能还会吃一些菜.
together ...and maybe a few dishes.
朱利:啊?
Julie: What!?
迈克:我开玩笑的.要不要亲吻一下,带点好运来?
Mike: I'm just kidding. OK, how about a kiss for luck?
朱利:你真的认为我们需要好运气吗?
Julie: Do you really think we'll need luck?
迈克:恩,需要非常非常多的好运气.
Mike: Oh, lots and lots of it.
卡罗:哪一个是你的?
Carol: Which one's yours?
本:两个都是.
Ben: Both of 'em.
卡罗:我还是不明白,
Carol: I still don't see why I have to eat in the living room with the
为什么一定要让我到客厅和巨鼠一起吃饭?
giant rat.
杰森:因为你是母亲,我想私下和...好好的谈谈.
Jason: You're mother and I would like to have a nice private talk...
麦琪:与迈克和他的狐狸精.
Maggie: With Mike and his scheming hussy.
杰森:我们不必老是把什么狐狸精,喂,
Jason: I don't think we have to use terms like scheming hu...he...
喂之类的话挂在嘴边吧...
hello, hello!!
麦琪:孩子们,孩子们,坐下,
Maggie: Kids, kids, sit down, sit down.
坐下.卡罗,帮我去看看克里斯!
Carol, would you please check on Chrissy for me!
卡罗:不去,每次都...
Carol: No, I always have...
麦琪:快去!!
Maggie: Just do it!!!
杰森:麦琪,我来帮着你给他们分美餐吧,
Jason: Maggie, why don't I help you serve this delicious meal you've been
你都花了整整一天的时间来准备呢.
preparing all day.
迈克:看看,现在你感觉到你的担心多余了吧?
Mike: There, now don't you feel silly for worrying?
杰森:好了,孩子们,快来尝尝妈妈的拿手菜---大豆和香肠.
Jason: Alright! Everybody help themselves here to your mother's all time famous. wieners and beans.
麦琪:恩,我原本打算弄点美味可口的东西吃吃,
Maggie: Well, I was going to make something tasty and delicious,
可是我又觉得你们俩应该要适应新口味了,所以我还是做了香肠.
but then I thought
maybe you two should get used to the crud most newly-weds eat. Wiener
杰森:好啦,现在说说我们请你们俩来吃晚餐的真正原因吧.
Jason: Alright, well, that brings us to the real reason that we invited you two over for dinner tonight.
迈克:爸爸,别磨蹭了,
Mike: Look, Dad, we already know the reasons,
我们已经知道原因了,有什么要问的尽管问吧.
so lets just let the yelling begin, OK?
杰森:哈,不,不,迈克,你别着急嘛.你这么急着...不觉得有些草率和鲁莽吗?对了,麦琪,我们是很开明的父母,对吧?
Jason: Ha, no, no, hold your horses, Mike. There's not gonna be any ranting or raving over what a stupid thing this is for you to rush into... Well, we're all open-minded here, right, Maggie?
麦琪:开明得像筛子似的
Maggie: Like a sieve!
杰森:因此,我列出了一个清单,
Jason: So, I have come up with a list of forty six items,
上面描述了46件"你还没有考虑清楚的事情."
of what I call, "Things you haven't thought enough about."
迈克:哈,爸爸,你为什么不给其他人也列一份呢?
Mike: Gee, Dad, don't you have copies for the rest of us?
杰森:事实上,我确是这样做的.这是你的,每个人都有一份.你可以根据注释,一条一条的看.如果有谁想多加几条你们自己的想法,这里有笔.现在从第一条开始,"为什么要现在结婚?"
Jason: As a matter of fact, I do. Here you go, everybody gets one. You can read along, follow the notes. If you wanna make a few of your own, here's a pen. Everybody, let's jump on number on here, "why get married now?"
迈克:我们还没有结婚.3个月后才会结.
Mike: We're not. We're getting married in three months.
杰森:好,那为什么要等3个月呢?
Jason: Alright, well why three months?
迈克:难道3个月后不可以吗?
Mike: Well, why not?
麦琪:这就是你的答案吗?哼,婚礼被取消,我们吃饭!
Maggie: That's it? That's your answer? Huh! The wedding's off, let's eat!
朱利:迈克的意思是说因为我们互相爱着对方.
Julie: Mike meant, because we're in love now.
迈克:对,没错,爸爸,我们互相爱着对方.
Mike: Yeah, Dad, we love each other!
杰森:在第38条,我有提出来,什么是真正的爱.
Jason: Well, I deal with what real love is in the corollary to question
所以,关于这个问题,我们可以略过.
thirty eight there. So we can just move on for now.
开始第二个问题,"结婚后,你们住哪里?"
Let's go to question two, "where will you live?"
朱利:住在我的公寓...我的意思是说"我们的"公寓.
Julie: At my apartment...I mean "our" apartment.
杰森:在我清单的第...中,涉及到了共同财产的问题
Jason: Well, I do cover community property in total in...
麦琪:杰森,你的香肠要变冷了!
Maggie: Jason, your wiener is getting cold!
杰森:啊,让我们接着看第三个问题,"将来你们靠什么来养活自己呢?"
Jason: Ah, let's take a look at question number three then; "how will you support yourselves?"
朱利:这个嘛,我现在的工作是照看克里斯,
Julie: Well, I have my job here as Chrissy's nanny,
在我上完课后,我还可以到哥伦比亚大学图书馆去兼职.
and I'm gonna get a job at Columbia University library, after classes.
麦琪:你愿意供养这个游手好闲的家伙吗?
Maggie: And you don't mind supporting this bum?
杰森:麦琪!
Jason: Maggie!
迈克:嗨,不要这样说我!阿迪的爸爸说过,如果我愿意的话,可以在周末的时候去他的建筑工地做事.每天的报酬是200美元!
Mike: Hey, come on! Eddy...Eddy's dad says that I can work for him on the weekends at his construction business. It pays like two hundred Dollars a day!
杰森:200元?好吧.让我们接着看问题四,"当你结婚后,有了全新的妻子,又要去兼职,那你们要怎么样来继续学习呢?"
Jason: Two hundred? Right, OK. Let's take a look at number four here, " how are you gonna keep up with your studies, when you have a brand new wife and a new part time job?"
迈克:爸爸,你也清楚,自从我认识朱利后,我的考试分数一次比一次高...所以,是她在促进我的学习!
Mike: Well look Dad, all I know is that ever since I met Julie, my grades have only gone up and up. I...I mean, she makes me study!
朱利:他甚至说,在学习上,我比你们更严厉.
Julie: He says I'm even tougher than you are.
麦琪:好吧,我们会拭目以待的.
Maggie: Well, we'll see, won't we?
(迈克,麦琪和朱利开始争论起来)
(Mike, Maggie and Julie are arguing.)
杰森:好了,不要吵了!让我们接着看第43条.
Jason: Ok!! Let's just move on to number forty three.
迈克:哦,能不能再给我一份?我把香肠汁溅在第43条上了!
Mike: Oh, can I have another copy? I got wiener juice on my forty three!
麦琪:拿去吧,拿我的!我们这是白费唇舌,一点用也没有!
Maggie: Here, take mine! This is getting us absolutely nowhere!
杰森:麦琪,我们答应过不对他们嚷嚷的,记得吗?
Jason: Maggie, we agreed we wouldn't yell at them, remember?
麦琪:杰森,除了桌子,和那滴滴滴滴香肠汁外,我们没有得到任何有用的答案!!
Maggie: Jason, between tabling, corollaries an an an an an wiener juice we've covered absolutely nothing!!!
杰森:哦,好呀,那你想要我怎么做呢?难道你希望我放弃这个理智的办法?对他们怒吼,他们将要犯下他们一生中最不可原谅的错误?
Jason: Oh, good, so what do you want me to do? You want me to just give up my calm rational approach? Should I just blurt out, they are about to make the biggest mistake of their lives!!!!????
迈克:一生中最不可原谅的错误?
Mike: The biggest mistake of our lives?
杰森:哦,迈克,你听我说,
Jason: Oh, come on, Mike, you know it's true!
你要明白我们说的是真的!你只是好奇,
I mean you get all swept up in a little forbidden romance and before you
所以才走进了目前对你来说还是被禁止的所谓浪漫中,当你弄明白后,你会发现你的婚姻会是多么的荒唐.
know it, ba-bing! ba-bang! ba-boom! Wow! And you're strolling down the isle!!
朱利:禁止的浪漫?
Julie: Forbidden romance!?
麦琪:我们是由于克里斯的需要才请你的,不是迈克的!
Maggie: We hired you to take care of Chrissy's needs, not...Mike's!
朱利:但是我也没有照顾迈克的需要呀!
Julie: I did not take care of Mike's needs!
迈克:够了,妈妈,你到底想要说什么?
Mike: Yeah, what the heck are you talking about Mom?
杰森:麦琪,你觉得我们有必要扯的那么远吗?
Jason: Do you think we need to get into that now?
麦琪:哦,杰森,不要干涉我要谈论的话题!
Maggie: Oh, Jason don't tell me what there's a need to get into!
迈克:我不会坐在这里听你们胡说八道了!我们走!
Mike: I will not sit here and listen to this! Come on!!
朱利:噢!!
Julie: Ow!!
杰森:好呀,一说到实质性的事情你就想逃避了!!
Jason: Oh, sure, when it gets a little tough you just turn tail and run!!
嗨,
Hey, if you can't stand your mother's poo poo,
如果你不好好的回答你妈妈的唠叨,你们的关系也会没戏了!!!
this relationship doesn't have a chance!!!
杰森:麦琪,厨房里的餐桌怎么又摆好了呀?我以为你说过要到外面去吃晚餐呢?
Jason: Maggie, why's the kitchen table set? I thought you said we were going out for dinner?
麦琪:不,我说过要你到外面去吃.
Maggie: No, I said you were going out for dinner.
杰森:对于说你唠叨,我已经跟你道过歉了呀.
Jason: I said I was sorry about that poo poo thing.
麦琪:杰森,跟道歉没有关系.
Maggie: Jason, it has nothing to do with that.
你要和迈克一起出去吃晚餐.
You're going out to dinner with Mike.
杰森:发生什么事了?
Jason: What's going on?
麦琪:没事,我只是想和朱利平静而友好的好好谈谈.
Maggie: Well, I just wanted to have a nice calm chat with Julie.
就如你知道的,就只我和她.
You know, just the two of us.
杰森:哈,没有证人?
Jason: Ah, no witnesses, huh?
麦琪:没有.你说我要不要在鹅肝中下毒呢?
Maggie: Yeah, right. You think I'd put arsenic in the goose-liver pate?
你来尝尝.
Here taste it.
杰森:恩,晚点再下吧.
Jason: Mmmm, na! Maybe later.
麦琪:你好.
Maggie: Herro.
迈克:妈妈好!
Mike: Herro.
杰森:你好!
Jason: Hi.
朱利:好呀.
Julie: Hiya.
迈克:呵,看来,到目前为止,一切都好嘛.
Mike: Ah. Well, so far, so good.
对了,爸爸,妈妈跟我说,你想跟我出去吃汉堡包?
So, Dad, Mom tells me that you wanna take me out for a burger.
杰森:对,她也跟我说过.
Jason: Yeah, she tells me that too.
麦琪:好了,迈克,杰森,你们可以走啦,我的烤鹅要焦了.
Maggie: Well, Mike, Jason, you two better get going. I'm gonna burn my roast.
外婆:大家好!
Grandma: Hello. Hello, hello!
迈克:嗨,外婆,外公好.
Mike: Hey, Grandma, Grandpa.
麦琪:妈,爸,你们来的太早了吧!
Maggie: Mom, Dad, you're early!
杰森:早?你好像没有跟我提过你父母要来呀?
Jason: Early? You didn't mention your parents were coming over.
外公:呵呵,你怎么样也应该表示出一点感激之情吧.
Grandpa: Well, you could be a little grateful here.
麦琪:爸爸.
Maggie: Dad.
杰森:感激?
Jason: Grateful?
外公:对,我的意思是说,我们不顾一切的赶来这里,就是为了填补被你们解雇的小保姆的空缺.
Grandpa: Ya. I mean, we dropped everything to get down here, to fill in for this nanny that you fired!
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
杰森:麦琪,这就是你所谓的平静的聊聊吗?原来你是要解雇她!
Jason: That's your idea of a calm chat? Firing the nanny!
迈克:得了,爸爸,你也别在这里装好人了.我们知道你是幕后主谋之一.
Mike: Ah, come on Dad! Don't start acting here. We know you're behind this whole thing too.
杰森:不,我不是.麦琪,
Jason: No, I am not. Tell him Maggie!
告诉他,我不是!整件事情都是你一手操纵的.
No, you did this nut bar thing on your own.
麦琪:是,这件事情是我一个人操纵的.
Maggie: I did this nut bar thing on my own.
外公:哦哦,我已经好久没见他们这么紧张了...恩,上次他们也这样.小姐,你知道是为什么吗?
Grandpa: Ooh, I haven't seen 'em this tense since...err...well the last time we were here. Do you know what this is about, Miss...err...
朱利:我们已经见过面了.我是朱利,是克里斯的小保姆,
Julie: We've met before Mr. Malone.
但是,你刚才跟我说,我已经被解雇了.
I'm Julie, Chrissy's nanny, till you tell me otherwise.
外公:呵呵,不足挂齿...哦...
Grandpa: Well, it's a pleasure... Oh...err...
麦琪:够了,够了,我一定要辞退她!去起诉我呀!
Maggie: OK, OK, so I was gonna hang her! Sew me!
迈克:妈妈,你不能辞退我未来的妻子!
Mike: Look, Mom, you cannot fire my future wife!
朱利:没关系.我主动辞职!
Julie: It's OK. I was gonna quit!
杰森:嗨,没有人要辞退谁的将来或是别的什么,行吗?
Jason: Hey, nobody's gonna fire anybody's future or anything, OK?
迈克:听着,你没有辞掉任何东西!!
Mike: Listen, you're not quitting anything!!
麦琪和朱利:不要告诉我该做什么!
Maggie and Julie: Don't tell me what to do!!!
外婆:打扰一下,我知道有些时候,我对某些事情的反应是有点迟钝...
Grandma: Excuse me. I know sometimes I'm slow catching on to things...
外公:只是有的时候?
Grandpa: Sometimes?
外婆:但是,我刚才好像听到你说你和迈克已经订婚了?
Grandma: But, did I just hear you say that you and Mike were engaged?
迈克:外婆,没错!
Mike: You bet Grandma!!
外婆:哈,真棒!
Grandma: Oh, that's wonderful!!
外公:好呀,现在是年轻人的时刻了!
Grandpa: Well, it's about time young man!
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
外婆:我就想你们快点给我生个曾孙.
Grandma: I want you two to make me a great-grandma real soon.
麦琪:妈妈,爸爸,你们这是在帮倒忙.
Maggie: Mom, Dad, you're not helping me out here.
杰森:麦琪,叫你爸妈来真是个超级棒的主意.
Jason: Super idea to call your parents, Maggie.
麦琪:哼,最少我为这件事做了点贡献,杰森.
Maggie: Well, at least I was doing something about it, Jason.
杰森:呵,我也为这件事情做了点贡献.
Jason: Well, I'm doing something about it too.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森:我...恩,正在考虑下一步该怎么办?
Jason: I'm...err...trying to think of the next logical step in this thing.
麦琪:等到你想出来的时候,他们俩已经高高兴兴的结婚了,
Maggie: Well, by the time you've thought of the next logical step,
到时,我们还能怎么样?
Mike and Julie will be happily married, and then what will we do?
迈克:哈哈,什么不能做了!!因为我们会开开心心的结婚.
Mike: Nothing!! Because we'll be happily married.
麦琪:迈克,不需要故意提高你的声音.
Maggie: Mike, there's no reason to raise your voice.
现在我们可以好好的,平静的,理性的谈谈了.
We can have a nice, calm, rational intercourse here.
外公:玛格丽特.
Grandpa: Margaret!!!!
麦琪:爸爸,你不要说话了!!!
Maggie: Daddy, just shut up!!!
外公:不,你看看你自己都这样子,我终于明白为什么你的孩子们会对你大喊大叫了.
Grandpa: No, now you see by that example, I can see why your children are yelling at you!!
杰森:就像我刚才说的,麦琪,真是好主意.
Jason: Like I said, Maggie, super idea.
迈克:大家都听好,你们想说什么就说吧,不管怎么样,
Mike: Listen, you guys can say whatever you want,
我和朱利一定要结婚!!!,如果实在不行,
but Julie and I are getting married!!!
我们就私奔,朱利,是吗?
I mean, we'll elope if we have to, right Julie?
朱利:迈克!
Julie: Mike!
迈克:我说的不是从现在算起的三个月以后哦,妈妈,
Mike: And I'm not talking about three months from now, Mom.
我说的是今晚.嘣嘣...
I'm talking about tonight. Ba-bing! Ba-bang! Err...
杰森:嘣.
Jason: Ba-boom.
迈克:嘣!对吧,朱利?
Mike: Ba-boom! Right Julie?
朱利:请原谅我们.
Julie: Excuse us.
迈克:嗨!
Mike: Hey!
外婆:家庭式婚礼,哦,你们一定会兴奋无比的.
Grandma: Family wedding, oh, you two must be so thrilled.
朱利:你怎么能说出那么不负责任的话呢,我们私奔?
Julie: How could you say something so crazy, like, we're eloping?
迈克:好了,你先冷静下来!
Mike: Look, would you just calm down!
朱利:你不认为觉得,有些事情我们应该先好好商量,
Julie: I mean, isn't that something we should talk about,
而不是胡乱说说而已?
instead of you just blurting it out?
迈克:知道了,知道了.我们以后再冷静而理性地商量,好吗?现在,你在想什么?
Mike: Yes, yes, we'll talk about it, OK? Calmly and rationally. So, what do you think?
朱利:我已经有6年没有订阅"新娘杂志"了,
Julie: I didn't subscribe to "Bride's Magazine" for six years,
如果只能在破旧不堪的,乌烟瘴气的教堂里举行婚礼吗?
just to end up in front of some justice of peace, in some scummy chapel,
我宁愿...
in some place where it smells bad!! I...I just...
迈克:等等,什么...什么...什么...你宁愿不结婚?
Mike: Wait, what...what...what...you'd rather just not get married at all?
朱利:是的.
Julie: Yes.
迈克:为什么?
Mike: What?
朱利:不.是的.我什么都不知道.我懂了,我们私奔吧.
Julie: No. Yes. I don't know. I know, let's just elope.
本:外婆,外公,我们都不知道你们要来哦.
Ben: Grandma, Grandpa, we didn't know you guys were coming.
杰森:不,显然这是个隐藏的很好的秘密了.
Jason: No, apparently that was a well guarded secret.
外公:卡罗,看来你马上就要多一个嫂子了.
Grandpa: So, Carol, looks like you're gaining a sister in law.
卡罗:恩,同时,也要少一个哥哥了.
Carol: And, losing a brother.
本:我马上要得到一个房间了.
Ben: I'm gaining an apartment.
外婆:现在我问你,朱利就是那个让你几个月来,
Grandma: Now, isn't this Julie the same girl you've been raving about
一直无法平复心情的姑娘吗?
all these months?
卡罗:除了她还有谁呀.
Carol: The very same.
外婆:麦琪,你不是好像说过,
Grandma: And Maggie, didn't you say once that you hoped Mike would meet
希望迈克能找到像朱利这样的好姑娘吗 ?
and settle down with a girl like Julie?
麦琪:妈妈,在我对你说过的那么多话中,
Maggie: Mom, of all the things I've ever said,
你为什么只记住了这一句!
you've picked that one to remember!
外公:迈克是个幸运的男人.
Grandpa: That Michael is a lucky man.
麦琪:他还不是幸运的男人!他只是个孩子!
Maggie: He is not a lucky man! He is a boy!
你们什么时候变的这么大度了?
And when did you two get so lenient?
外婆:我们俩一直都是大度的.
Grandma: We've always been lenient.
麦琪:妈妈,爸爸,你们长途跋涉,从200里外赶来,就是为了来折磨我们的吗?
Maggie: Mom, Dad, did you two drive two hundred miles just to torment us?
外公:嘿嘿,幸好我知道有一条近路,只要走183里就到了.
Grandpa: With the short-cuts I know, this old copper's cut that down to about a hundred and eighty three.
麦琪:爸妈,你们为什么不向右转,开回波士顿?
Maggie: Mom, Dad, why don't you two turn right around and go back to Boston!
外公:麦琪!麦琪!亲爱的,什么事情让你这么烦恼呀?
Grandpa: Maggie! Maggie! Dear, is something bothering you?
麦琪:别问了!不要再问了!
Maggie: Stop! Stop it!
杰森:麦琪,别这样!要是以前你要让你父母回家,我一定会拍手称快,并迫不及待的去道别.但是,今天晚上,我认为你离你原本的目的越来越远了.
Jason: Maggie, Come on! Now, under normal circumstances I would applaud you telling your parents to hit the road. Heck, I'd do the wave! But, I think tonight, you have strayed from your original purpose.
麦琪:谢谢你的提醒!让我们快点找到她,然后辞退她!
Maggie: You're right! Let's find her and fire her!
杰森:不!!麦琪,
Jason: No!! Maggie, no!
你看,平静,理性的讨论后又怎么样?
Look, come on, whatever happened to the calm, rational discussion?
晚餐中的开心闲聊又怎么样?还有我们的晚餐怎么解决?
Whatever happened to the little chat over dinner? What happened to dinner?
麦琪:我,我肯定她一定恨死我了,
Maggie: Well I...I figured she'd never make it past the pate.
不会再原谅我了.其实,
Look, I don't feel so great about what I just did.
我对自己的所作所为也不齿.
But I am worried to death about Mike.
可是,我就是情不自禁的要担心迈克.
He's this sweet kid,
他是个可爱的孩子,还不能承受婚姻会带来的考验和折磨.
who's nowhere near ready for the trials and tribulations of marriage.
杰森:是,我明白你.
Jason: Hey, I know that.
麦琪:杰森,难道你不记得我们结婚的第一年所承受的苦难了吗?不记得那些痛苦了吗?我们那时几乎要放弃婚姻了.我真的只是太爱他,不想看他受到一点点的伤害.
Maggie: Jason, do remember how tough our first year together was? Remember the pain? We almost didn't make it. I just love him so much, I don't wanna see him hurt.
杰森:宝贝,我也不想,那是...
Jason: Nor do I honey, that's...
麦琪:但是你认为他不会继续...
Maggie: But you don't think he should go ahead and...
杰森:不,不,不会.
Jason: No, no, not at all.
但是,我认为他们俩应该听听你刚才对我所说的一番话.
No, but I do think those two should hear what you just said to me.
并且,我认为我们4个人需要坐下来...好好的讨论要怎么来解决这件事情.
Now, I think the four of us should sit down and...and talk this out together.
麦琪:你说的没错.
Maggie: You're right.
外公:好了!冰释前嫌!
Grandpa: Alright! Now freeze!!
杰森:哦,阿迪,你不会打算让我把刚才的话重复一遍吧?
Jason: Oh, Ed, you're not gonna tell me to spread 'em again, are you?
外公:如果我不得不那样做的话!!呵,
Grandpa: If I have to!! But, enough of this malarkey!
废话少说!在我看来呀,
I think the four of you should be together in the same room,
你们四个确实应该呆在同一个房间,好好的把这麻烦的事情解决.
to talk this damn blasted thing out!!
杰森:阿迪,我完全同意你的看法.
Jason: Ed, I couldn't agree with you more.
外公:好.退缩的家伙想要拉什么出来呀?
Grandpa: OK. What's the head shrinker trying to pull?
麦琪:没什么,爸爸.
Maggie: Nothing, Daddy.
外婆:你知道吗,我刚才在想...
Grandma: You know, I was just thinking...
杰森:哦..
Jason: Oh.
外婆:真是太有趣了.哈哈哈...
Grandma: This is all so funny. Ha ha ha.
你对迈克未婚妻的反应,就像我当初对杰森...
You are reacting to Mike's fiancé, just as I reacted to Jason.
麦琪:哈!我曾经有说过朱利是一个想成为二流摇滚歌星的嘻皮鼻涕虫吗?
Maggie: Ha! Did I ever call Julie a hippy sleaze ball, who wanted to be some second-rate rock star?!!
杰森:二流的?我是不是也对迈克说过,"
Jason: Second-rate?Have I ever said to Mike, "until you regain your senses,
在你恢复意识前,我们为你做决定!年轻人,
we will do the thinking for you!
我们要将这件事情在萌芽状态解决.杰森?"
Young man, it's time to nip this thing in the bud!!"
杰森:你听过我用新的唱片机录的样歌吗?
Jason: Did you ever hear that demo I cut with the new bass player?
麦琪:没有,我不会去听的!因为我决不会以那样的方式和我儿子说话!
Maggie: No, I haven't! Because I would never talk that way to my son!
外公:你们不用再争啦.我的意思是说,
Grandpa: You don't have to say another word.
你为什么要下去,然后被当作小孩一样来对待呢?
I mean, why should you go down there and be treated like a child?
迈克:是!
Mike: Yeah!
外公:为什么你为了这只狐狸精,
Grandpa: Why should you be subjected to that,
就不顾一切了呢?
just for defending this little tramp?
朱利:什么?
Julie: What?
迈克:喂!听着,你说的可是我未来的妻子!
Mike: Hey! Listen, that's my future wife you're talking about!!
外公:迈克,就我们俩来说,你不会和这样的女孩子结婚.
Grandpa: Mike, just between the two of us; you don't marry girls like this.
朱利:这样的女孩!!
Julie: Gals like this!!
迈克:喂,外公,虽然我很爱你,
Mike: Hey, listen Grandpa, as much as I love you,
但是,只要你再说一次她的坏话,我会毫不留情的打你了.
you say another word and I'm gonna have to hit you!!
外公:来呀,你们根本就不能肯定,
Grandpa: Come on, you can't honestly tell me,
你们的婚姻是对的!
you think this marriage is a good idea!
迈克:我肯定是,
Mike: I sure can, I think it's a great idea!
我认为我们的婚姻是伟大的!没有人能改变我娶朱利的决心,
And nothing and nobody is gonna stand in the way of me marrying Julie,
因为我们爱着对方.
because I love her.
外公:好了,你跟我说这些有什么用呢?下去吧,去告诉你的父母,关于你的想法!
Grandpa: Well, what are you talking to me for? Go down there and tell your parents that!
迈克:我会的!我们走,朱利!外公,谢谢你.
Mike: I will! Let's go Julie! Hey, Grandpa, thanks.
外公:谢什么呀?
Grandpa: For what?
朱利:叫我护理精.
Julie: Calling me a tramp.
外公:我乐意.呵
Grandpa: My pleasure.
杰森:哈哈,真好,我们四个人终于能坐下来,好好的谈谈了.
Jason: Yep, well, I for one am glad that we're all finally sitting down to reason together.
麦琪:首先,我要对我之前的过激行为跟你们道歉.
Maggie: And I want to apologize for being over-emotional earlier.
那都是出于我对迈克的爱.
It's just out of my love for Mike.
朱利:我能了解.
Julie: I can relate to that.
麦琪:是的.
Maggie: Right.
杰森:好了,好了.
Jason: Yes, well, just to make sure that this thing starts off right,
一切事情都进展顺利,我还想说的是,我们答应你们的婚事.
I wanna say that, we accept the fact that you two are gonna get married.
麦琪和朱利:什么?
Maggie and Julie: What?
朱利:噢..
Julie: Wow.
迈克:等等,等等.我敢打赌这肯定是个圈套.
Mike: Hey, wait a minute, wait a minute. I bet there's a catch.
杰森:放轻松.这的确有一个圈套.
Jason: Relax. There's a catch.
迈克:我早就知道了.
Mike: I knew it.
杰森:迈克,让我们再看看整件事情,
Jason: Well, look the whole issue here Mike, is really one of timing.
最关键的就是时间问题.我的意思是,你们为什么要在3个月后结婚?
I mean why do you wanna get married in three months? Why not wait a year?
为什么不等到一年后?为什么你们要这么急着跳进婚姻呢?
Why do you wanna jump into this thing?
迈克:爸爸,你看,你又来了,跳进婚姻,我不是跳的,行不行?你看见屋里有人在跳了吗?我们可都是坐的好好的呢.
Mike: See, there you go again Dad, just jump into this thing. I am not jumping, OK? Do you see anyone in this room who is jumping? We're all sitting!
杰森:迈克.
Jason: Mike.
迈克:看,我可不希望明明是坐在这里,
Mike: Look, I am not gonna sit here and be accused of jumping when I am
却被责备说我在跳!!
clearly sitting!!
杰森:好啦,让我来重申一下我的问题:现在对你们来说,计划结婚合适吗?
Jason: Alright, let me rephrase the question; is this the right time for you to be planning a wedding?
麦琪:计划?他们压根就没有计划过!!
Maggie: Planning? They haven't planned didley!!
杰森:麦琪!
Jason: Maggie!
麦琪:当我知道他们没有好好的计划时,
Maggie: Well, I'm not gonna sit here silently,
我决不能坐视不理!!
when I know they haven't planned didley!!
迈克:妈妈,你不是坐着的,你是站着的哦!
Mike: You're not sitting, you're standing!
杰森:哦,好了,
Jason: Oh, come on, both of you!!
你们俩都住口!!
Now remember a little while ago,
还记不记得我刚刚说过,要采取下一步高招吗?
I said I wanted to take the next logical step to this thing?
麦琪:然后呢?
Maggie: And?
杰森:然后,就没有下一步了!
Jason: And, there is no next logical step to this thing!
麦琪:谢谢你,医生.这是属于你的一百块.
Maggie: Thank you Doctor. Here's one hundred Dollars.
杰森:麦琪,我认为我们应该认识到,他们都不是小孩子了,他们已经成人了.
Jason: Maggie, what I mean is, we've got to start from scratch! They're not kids anymore, they're adults.
麦琪:是的.但是我认为他们做错了,并且,你也错了.如果你愿意指出来的话,那我来.
Maggie: Yes, Jason! Now, but I think they're wrong and I know you do too. And if you won't say it, then I will.
杰森:我愿意.你要先等等了.
Jason: I'll say it. You should wait.
迈克:不管你说什么,我都不会在乎了.
Mike: I don't care what you say.
不管发生什么事情,我和朱利都会结婚的!!
Julie and I are getting married, no matter what!!
麦琪:我说,
Maggie: And, I say,
在你没有恢复正常前,我们会替你做决定,
until you regain your senses we will do the thinking for you!
现在是时候那这件事情毁灭在初期了!
Young man, it's time to nip this thing in the bud!
迈克:把这件时期毁灭在初期?
Mike: Nip this thing in the bud?
麦琪:哦,我的天呀!我真的和我妈一样,都说了相同的话.
Maggie: Oh, my God! It's true, you do turn into your mother.
毁灭在初期,杰森,你最后一次是什么时候听到这句话的?
Nip it in the bud; Jason, when was the last time you heard that?
杰森:我不知道了,好像是5分钟前在厨房听到过.
Jason: I don't know...five minutes ago in the kitchen.
麦琪:不是,不是.应该是20年前,在我父母的厨房里.我,我不能重蹈覆辙;我不能把我的经历再加在你们的身上.迈克,妈妈不会再反对你们了.
Maggie: No! No, twenty years ago in my parent's kitchen. I...I can't do this; I can't do to them, what was done to us. Mike, I am not going to stand in your way.
朱利:你不反对了?
Julie: You're not?
麦琪:不了.
Maggie: No.
迈克:啊,现在又要玩什么圈套呀?
Mike: Well, what's the catch this time?
麦琪:不是圈套.
Maggie: There's no catch.
迈克:也就是说,你们支持我们结婚?
Mike: So, you're saying you approve of this marriage.
麦琪:我不同意3个月后.但是呢,
Maggie: Not in three months I don't.
我保证我再也不会说一句不好的话.
But, you will never hear another bad word about it from me.
迈克:爸爸,你呢?
Mike: Dad?
杰森:我和你妈妈保持统一.
Jason: I'm with your mother.
迈克:这只是一个好的开始.
麦琪:朱利,欢迎成为我们家的一员.
00:21:11,900
Mike: But it's a start. Maggie: Julie, welcome to the family.